izat Borhanud



Summary_

Electrical & Computer Engineering graduate who specialized in Power Electronics and Control Systems. 1+ year work experience in traffic control company and additionally, in the food-service industry. I have vast interests in Electronics, Power Engineering, Renewable Energy, Automation, and Energy Sustainability. I am incredibly adaptable to any situation, have worked with people from different countries and backgrounds on engineering projects throughout my undergraduate studies. The ultimate goal in my career is to become an awesome and hard-working engineer so that I could improve the lives of fellow Malaysians and beyond.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Electrical & Computer Engineering

Columbus, Ohio, USA

Jan. 2015 - May. 2019

THE OHIO STATE UNIVERSITY

- CGPA: 3.30/4.00, 2nd-Class Upper
- Dean's List Spring Semester 2019
- · Major courses: Power Electronics, Control Systems Theory, Advanced Digital Design, Electrical Machines, Feedback Control Design, AC Power Systems, Sustainable Energy & Power Systems

American Degree Foundation Program

Shah Alam, Selangor

Aug. 2013 - Dec. 2014

INTEC EDUCATION COLLEGE

CGPA: 3.19/4.00, 2nd-Class Upper

Sijil Pelajaran Malaysia

Seri Hartamas, Kuala Lumpur

Jan. 2008 - Dec 2012

SEKOLAH MENENGAH KEBANGSAAN SERI HARTAMAS

• SPM score: 3A+, 4A, 1A-, 1B+

Projects

Capstone: Solar Tracker

Columbus, Ohio, USA

PROJECT LEADER

Jan. 2019 - May. 2019

- Designed a portable solar panel that automatically tracks the movement of a light source.
- Manufactured the movable parts to achieve dual-axis movements for the prototype using a 3D Builder software.
- Designed & implemented the circuit diagram which consisted of four 100 kOhm resistors & photoresistors connected in a voltage divider fashion.
- · Managed project deadlines, handled budget constraints & coordinated tasks for each team member in the group project.

Electric Vehicle Super Car

Columbus, Ohio, USA

PROJECT COORDINATOR

Apr. 2019 - May. 2019

- Managed to achieve the goal set by the instructor, to improve the top speed of the electric super car to more than 250 mph.
- Spearheaded the increase in top speed for the electrical super car by 5.6% (264 mph) through analysis of the electrical and mechanical power, peak current, and machine torque.
- · Simulated the motor performance of the brushless DC motor through MATLAB coding to analyze the systems characteristics.

Advanced Energy Vehicle (AEV)

Columbus, Ohio, USA Jan. 2016 - May. 2016

ТЕАМ МЕМВЕР

- Designed & built an autonomous electric vehicle transportation system following strict requirements as required by the clients.
- · Analyzed performance of the vehicle using MATLAB & collaborated with teammates to improve vehicle performance using C programming.
- Wrote the Bill of Materials & designed the vehicle model based on the design specifications using SolidWorks.

Work Experience

Sena Traffic Systems Sdn. Bhd.

Sri Petaling, Kuala Lumpur

JUNIOR ELECTRICAL ENGINEER

May. 2018 - Aug. 2018

- · Implemented circuit configuration and wiring for streetlight troubleshooter according to the designed schematics.
- Worked alongside senior engineers in the design of a zero-crossing detector for an automated lighting system.
- · Troubleshooted and reconfigured damaged PCBs of high-powered 220V 240V traffic controller circuits.

Podgy & The Banker Coffee Shop

Seri Hartamas, Kuala Lumpur

BARISTA

May. 2016 - Aug. 2016

- · Handled customers orders while maintaining a high-level of service in a fast-paced restaurant environment.
- · Learned effective communication skills to ensure food order operations run smoothly.



Software Programming Languages

Microsoft Office LaTeX 00000 Matlab/Simulink C++ 00000 AutoDesk Eagle Arduino IDE 00000 00000 Arduino IDE VHDL 00000 •••00 SolidWorks 00000 Python 0000 AutoCAD Electrical 00000 HTML/CSS •0000

Languages

English	•••••
Malay	•••••